

## Andrew Padalka, iOS Developer

## hesitantsharona@gmail.com

### **SUMMARY**

An iOS-developer with 4 years experience of developing native applications using Xcode and Swift programming language in cross-functional teams of companies, building products for mobile users. The products were managed with Scrum and Agile approach, had API-based backends communicating with JSON-formatted data via HTTPS between different software components.

## Relevant Experience

Nuvo Group Ltd., (Tel Aviv, State of Israel), Kiev, Ukraine — April 2021 – August 2021, — iOS engineer

- Participated in developing of iOS application for a sensor's belt allowing to conduct medical monitoring of the pregnant women.
- My responsibility was to take part in discussions to refine design requirements for the features, planned to include in the next release.
- To take already estimated tasks, implement them in the project, test locally on available devices, sent to code review (gitlab), after approve to take the next task. Prepare the app for QA's test. And after their approve to submit the app into the Appstore.
- At the end of the sprint, I was to prepare the demonstration of the changes, I implemented in that sprint to the English-speaking audience of my team-mates and main office staffs representatives (i.e designer and CEO) live-casting from the real device.
- I was the second developer on the project. At the point I joined the team, the project has been developing for 2 years or so. It used cocoapods alongside with Carthage. The following dependencies were already added: SwiftLint, MQTTClient, Lottie-ios, Alamofire, Swinject, Auth0, JWTDecode, RxSwift, RxDataSource (via Carthage), Firebase/Analitics, Firebase/Crashlitics (via cocoapods). In this list I added Firebase/Messaging for implementing remote push notifications.
- To write Unit tests for different services.

# +380 (50) 562-82-36

## Andrew Padalka, iOS Developer

## hesitantsharona@gmail.com

<u>Pillars For Life Limited</u>, (Manchester, United Kingdom), Kiev, Ukraine — November 2019 – March 2021, — iOS developer

The Startup tried to build a platform for pretty complicated service, which would allow the users, related to the Global Muslim Community to place orders for performing certain religious ritual called 'Badal' behalf the user, and any volunteer, living in Mecca and having free time - to take such order and perform the ritual, providing the photos, videos and geo-data, gathered during the performance as a proof of the proper performance.

- I developed iOS apps for the user and for the volunteer as Prove of Concept, which allowed the performer indicate that his performance is right about to start, to take photos or videos during the every stage of this ritual, collect geo-data changes and data from sensors, switch from GPS to iBeacons at the certain point, and to inform performer, that all collected data is prepared and ready to be uploaded via not expensive internet-connection to the server.
- Reviewed code, designed by another team, found performance or logic issues (has to relly only on provided design, no Unit and/or UI tests were provided), violations of the Apple Guidelines, fixed them, refactored code, and rolled-out applications to the app store. Localised native app UI from English into Arabic (RTL) with the proper navigation.
- The following frameworks were used in this project: CoreLocation, GoogleMap, MapKit, GeoFencing for getting location updates and visualise users's track. Indoor location by using iBeacons, SensorKit and MotionKit for collecting data from device's sensors. Device's camera with AVFoundation and CoreVideo, CoreMedia. Video-streaming via dedicated 3d-party API-service (Wowza.com). NWPathMonitor, Alamofire, Codable/Decodable custom types for transforming in- app data into JSON for posting to BackEnd and vice versa. OperationQueue with dependent operations. Remote Push-Notifications via Google Cloud Platform and OneSignal. Handling notifications with deep links, navigating to a proper controller presenting an in-app objects.

# +380 (50) 562-82-36

# Andrew Padalka, iOS Developer

## hesitantsharona@gmail.com

<u>Doctor online, TOV</u>, Kiev, Ukraine — **September 2019 – October 2019,** — iOS developer

The startup has the goal to built the service to provide communication channels between the patient and doctors, I was suppose to boost the developers team, particularly because of using 3d-party WebSocket SDK - Start-Chat. This SDK has limited evaluation period.

- Led efforts in developing a native iOS-app for a Telemedicine product from scratch in collaboration with 2 more iOS team-mates.
- Divided Storyboards into small ones to reduce merge conflicts. Designed project structure for convenient navigation and collaboration. Participated in making decisions regarding of using

3d party libraries using Cocoapod. Deployed fastlane on a private Gitlab-server for CI/CD purposes. Used Gitflow

<u>It4Medicine</u>, Kiev, Ukraine — **January 2018 – August 2019**, — iOS developer

The main goal of this startup was to give doctors the mobile tool, that included medical data such as ICD10, ICPC-2 references, list of affordable drugs and lab-tests, that allowed them to keep all data related to their patients in one place, and this data would include the patients contacts, their appointments, lab tests, prescribed drugs and diagnoses history. The apps, we built with "offline first" principle in mind.

- In collaboration with cross functional team, made decisions regarding of ways to implement required features for a software Medical product. Using Agile approach, provided development timeline estimation and deliver on time.
- Redesigned user flow and UI of an existing native iOS-app according to changed design prototypes and built and maintained reusable, and reliable code
- Implemented custom UI-component for schedule, GANT-diagram. Localised UI on English and Ukrainian languages.
- Rolled-out application to the Appstore, deployed fastlane for CI/CD purposes. Considering users data migration on updates after installing new app releases.



# Andrew Padalka, iOS Developer

## hesitantsharona@gmail.com

### Education

- NATIONAL AEROSPACE UNIVERSITY "KHARKIV AVIATION INSTITUTE" BACHELORS DEGREE ON FACULTY OF AIRCRAFT CONTROL SYSTEMS, KHARKIV, 1992-1998
- OBJECTIVE-C FROM SCRATCH, WEB ACADEMY COURSES, KYIV, 2015
- SWIFT FROM SCRATCH, WEB ACADEMY COURSES, KYIV, 2016
- WORKSHOP "REDUX ARCHITECTURE FOR IOS", SIGMA SOFTWARE UNIVERSITY, KYIV, JANUARY 2018
- DOMAIN MEETUPS: E-HEALTHCARE #1, WHIRL SOFTWARE, KYIV, DECEMBER 2018